-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: 千欲 小黄不小黄 夏至未寒 肉肉君 喵喵
校对: 你们茶前辈
今天是个最好的日子
Today is best day ever.
搬家日!
Moving Day!
谁搬家?
For who?
答案是: 所有波星人
Answer: The Boov.
波星人是什么人?
Who are the Boov?
答案: 最牛的宇宙流浪种族
Answer: Best species ever at running away.
所有的波星人移居者 请到您指定的港口
All Boov settlers, please report to your assigned transport.
每人只允许带一件行李
You are allowed one carry-on.
借过 抱歉
Excusing me. Sorries.
借过 抱歉 朋友
Excusing me. Pardon the me, friend.
波星人从没有朋友
Boov do not friend.
抱歉
Uh-oh. Sorries.
我是谁? 我叫小欧
Who am I? I am Oh.
很多朋友都这么叫我 于是我便有了这名字
I has been given this name by my many, many friends.
- 早上好!  - 欧
- Good morning!  - Oh.
- 嘿 伙计们  - 欧
- Hi, guys.  - Oh.
- 你好  - 欧
- Hello.  - Oh.
又能住进新家了 我太兴奋了!
I am very excitement to make a new fresh start!
这次的星球非常适合躲藏
We are all moving to best planet ever for to hiding.
我们的新家!
Our new home!
船长斯麦克!
Captain Smek!
我的波星人同志们!
My fellow Boov!
我再次地拯救了大家
I has saved us again.
低一点
A bit lower.
不 停下!
No, stop!
高一点 高一点
Up a bit. Up a bit.
好了 别动了 别动了
Perfect. Walk away. Walk away.
我的同志...
My fellow...
我的...
My...
同志...
fellow...
波星人们
Boov.
好消息!
Good news!
在我英明的领导下...
Thanks to my leadership skills...
我们畏缩 逃跑 颠沛流离...
cowering, running and pulling a skedaddle...
安全躲避了我们的天敌...
we are safe from our enemy...
瓜星人
the Gorg.
肮脏
Nasty.
给爷来点掌声!
Give Daddy some sugar!
船长斯麦克又拯救了我们!
Captain Smek has saved us again!
我们来到了牛奶系（指银河系）最适合隐藏的地方
We are now arrived at the best hiding place yet in the Milky Way.
而瓜星人最受不了乳糖
And the Gorg are lactose intolerant.
我太有才了!
Genius!
他们永远也找不到我们
They will never find us here.
谢谢
Thank you!
而且...
Best of yet...
这个星球好东西特别多
this planet is full of great stuff.
看这种美味的水果!
Look at these delicious fruits!
我感觉真棒!
That makes me feel so good.
要是聚会上吃多有意思!
What fun at a party!
波星人从不聚会
Boov do not party.
这星球上有居民
Also, this planet is inhabited.
但不用担心
But do not worry.
那些纯洁的土著很容易满足的
The native savages are simple and backwards.
看上去很丑 但挺可爱的!
They are so ugly, they are cute!
他们的所有信息可在这个...
Everything you need to know about them can be found...
小册子里找到
in these comprehensive pamphlets.
综合手册 综合手册
Comprehensive pamphlet. Comprehensive pamphlet.
我们的到来是他们的幸运
They are lucky the Boov have come.
好了 波星人 入侵倒数
All right, Boov. Invade on three.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
开心吧 人类! 波星人来了!
Rejoice, humanspeople! The Boov are arrived!
现在我们暂时地关闭一下重力场...
Now we are turning off your gravity temporarily...
好让你们搬迁得更轻松
so as to make your mandatory relocation easier.
更有趣!
And more fun!
那么 准备好了吗?
So, what is up?
好了!
You are!
别想抓住我!
You'll never catch me!
在送你们去人类镇的旅途中...
Enjoy you the frozen, sweetened bovine secretion...
请品尝波星人牌冰淇淋
as we take this short flight to Happy Humanstown.
船长斯麦克的欢乐人类镇
好酷啊! 快点!
This is so cool! Come on!
人类们将会在人类镇上永远幸福快乐地生活下去
Humanspersons are happiness and joy forever in Happy Humanstown.
欢迎来到你的新家
Welcome to your new home.
- 等下 什么? 不!  - 新家?
- Wait, what? No!  - New home?
其余的土地将会是波星人的
And rest of planet is for Boov.
双赢!
Win-win!
欢迎 波星人殖民者
Welcome, Boov settlers.
所有人类已经转移
All humans have been relocated.
你们的家已经安置完
Your homes are now ready.
谢谢!
Thanking you!
也许这个星球还需要小调整...
This planet may be a bit of a fixing-it-upper...
但没关系
but that is okay.
波星人很擅长于区分哪些东西有用
Boov are best at deciding what is useful.
哪些没用
And what is not.
走开 我们是清扫队的
Step aside. Clean-up crew.
没用
Useless.
今天 我开始了新生活
Today, I starts a new life.
新朋友 新家
With new friends. In a new home.
居民现在可以进入179区
Residents may now enter sector 179.
我住那!
That is me!
这就是为什么今天是好日子!
And that is why today is best day ever!
欢迎回家 邻居们!
Welcome home, neighbors!
波星人没有邻居
Boov do not have "neighbors."
那是因为上个星球的地形所致
That is owing to the size and topography of our former planet.
嗨! 我能借点糖吗?
Hey! Can I borrowing a cup of sugar?
说啥?
What?
现在 离得这么近总会培育出友谊的
But now, our closer proximity can leads to friendship.
现在我邀请大家...
You are all invited...
参加我的乔迁派对
to my warming of house party.
那么5点钟吧?
Say, 5:00?
好
Sure.
好的!
Yes!
欢迎波星人伙伴!
烹饪书
嗨 小猪! 在上面小心点!
Hey, Pig! Be careful up there!
抱歉 小猪
I'm sorry, Pig.
妈妈不在
Mom's not here.
这只是录像
It's just a video.
妈妈 小猪想和我们一起玩儿
Hey, Mom. I think Pig wants to join us.
那可不好玩!
It's not funny!
小钱!
Tip!
加油 妈妈 只是雪而已
Come on, Mom. It's just snow.
我从没见过雪
I don't know anything about snow.
我们住巴巴多斯的! 那儿没有雪!
We're from Barbados! We don't have snow!
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
我要把这个发给所有人
I'm sending this to everyone.
195区现在可以入住了
Sector 195 is ready for occupation.
等不了妈妈了 小猪 我们走
We can't wait for Mom, Pig. We gotta go.
现在!
Right now!
搬了新家! 圣诞快乐
小钱送给妈妈的礼物
哦不!
Oh, no!
准备跳舞!
Prepare for your dance attack!
好吧 让我们去找妈妈
Okay, let's go find Mom.
欢迎波星人们 游戏 零食 进来吧!
邻居们 你们好!
Neighbors, hello!
请进吧...
Please come in and...
你好
Hello.
有人吗?
Hello?
向右 向左 向左
And right. And left. Other left.
凯尔!
Kyle!
右 哦 左
Right. No, left.
你好 凯尔 我的朋友
Hello, friend Kyle.
我不是你朋友
I am not your friend.
你当然是 我们经常愉快地聊天
Of course you are. We have had many enjoyable talks.
不 我跟你说话是因为我不可以走开
No, we talk only because I'm not allowed to move.
你真是太有意思了
You are always saying the funny things.
也许你可以今晚来我家聚会
Perhaps you can say them at my warming of house party tonight.
我不去 聚会没有用 还浪费时间
I will not. Parties are useless and take up valuable Boov time.
看你那么忙 我就发个邮件给你...
Since you are at your busyness, I shall send an e-vite to you...
等你有空了再去
so you can join later during your leisure minute.
不要发 我空闲了也不会去
Please do not send. I enjoy my leisure minute.
伐嗒! 我把地址发送出去了
Fa-da! I have sent directions to my living space.
你把地址发送给每个人?
You sent directions to everyone?
什么? 这不是我的错
What? It is not my fault.
为什么"发送"旁边有个"全体发送"?
Why for put "send" button right next to "send all"?
一不小心就会按错的
This is just bad design.
你的邀请发送给了全银河系!
Your invite has been sent to entire galaxy!
惨了
Uh-oh.
的确惨了!
"Uh-oh" is right!
我们敌人瓜星人也会收到...
Our enemy, the Gorg, will receive it...
他们会找到我们的!
and can use directions for to find us!
瓜星人?
The Gorg?
伐嗒!
Fa-da!
你将会毁了我们波星人的!
You have doomed our species!
不 别
No, please.
我不是故意的 我很抱歉!
I did not mean to. I am sorries!
逮捕你!
You are arresting!
不!
No!
我只是想邀请你去...
I was just trying to invite you to my...
安全受到威胁
Security has been compromised.
逮捕那个波星人!
Arrest that Boov!
自动飞行器 我需要帮助!
Autopilot, I needs help!
巴黎的波星人总部有各种帮助服务
Help is available in Paris at Boov Headquarters.
不! 别去巴黎!
No, Autopilot! Any place but Paris!
你必须带我去一个没有波星人的地方
You must takes me to a place with no Boovs.
这个星球没有波星人的地方是南极
The only remaining spot on planet with no Boov is Antarctica.
来抱一个!
Group hug!
好的! 南极不错! 带我去那!
Yes! Antarctica is perfect! Take me there now!
不好意思 您是波星人逃犯
I am sorry. You are fugitive Boov.
开启自毁程序
Initiating Self-Destruct.
不! 别开启!
No! Do not initiate!
我不是逃犯!
I am not a fugitive!
不!
No!
哦不
Oh, no.
逮住你啦!
Gotcha, gotcha, gotcha!
为什么把我关起来?
What for are you did this?
我是波星人 所有人爱戴的
I am Boov, beloved by all humans.
我知道你是谁
I know what you are.
好极了! 那我能出来吗?
Excellent! Can I come into the out now?
不 你不能出来
No, you cannot "come into the out" now.
你永远都关在里面吧!
You can never come into the out, ever again!
我能出来!
But I can!
只要你把那条木杆拿走
You are just having to take away the piece of wood.
不然我只好...
Then I will have to...
从眼睛里射出镭射激光了!
I will shoot forth the lasers from my eyeballs!
你能吗?
You can do that?
当然
Yes.
如果你能射激光 那我没办法只好...
If you shoot your eye lasers, then I'll have no choice...
让你脑袋爆炸了!
but to explode your head!
- 你们人类不能让...  - 我们可以!
- You humans cannot to explode...  - We can too!
只是不经常用
We just don't much.
那样很没礼貌
It's considered rude.
那我们停战吧
Then I am granting you a truce.
你不用爆我的头...
You are not to exploding heads...
我也不用我的毁灭激光
and I will not do my devastating eye lasers.
好吧 停战
Okay. Truce.
- 那我能出来了吗?  - 不!
- So, can I come into the out now?  - No!
这是你们偷别人星球 绑架家人的惩罚
This is what you get for stealing planets and abducting people.
这是一个误会
You are thinking a mistake.
波星人从不偷窃和绑架
Boov do not steal and abduct.
波星人解放人们 和人们交朋友
No, Boov liberate and befriend.
猜猜谁做的!
Guess who made this one!
好漂亮!
This is so beautiful!
妈妈! 怎么了?
Mom! What's happening?
我不知道 亲爱的
I don't know, honey.
小钱!
Tip!
会没事的
It will be okay.
发现生命体 非人类 继续探索
Life form detected. Not human. Move along.
在送你们去人类镇的旅途中...
Enjoy you the frozen, sweetened bovine secretion...
请品尝波星人牌冰淇淋
as we take this short flight to Happy Humanstown.
妈妈!
Mom!
都是你们的错
It's all your fault.
你们绑架了我妈妈!
You stole my mom!
再见了 波星人
Smell ya later, Boov.
别! 现在就见面吧!
Wait! Smell me now!
我可以修好你的车子 我看见你把它弄坏了
I can to fixing your car. I seen you has broken it.
我没有弄坏它 我开车可溜了
I didn't break it. I'm a very good driver.
它漏油是正常的
It's supposed to leak like that.
我能出来了吗?
Can I come into the out now?
我了解那个波星人逃犯又犯了弥天大错...
I know the fugitive Boov has made yet another in a series of horrible...
虽然不是故意的
yet unintentionally humorous mistakes.
但我向你们保证 信号的传播已经...
But let me reassure you, the signal he broadcast...
得到遏制
is being handled.
我们还没有灭亡
We are definitely not doomed.
- 结束直播  - 我们完啦!
- And we're out.  - We are doomed!
瓜星人将会找到我们!
The Gorg are going to find us again!
那个疯子波星人毁了一切
The maniac Boov has ruined everything.
真糟糕
This is bad.
距离送达时间: 38小时16分钟
我真的挺爱这个星球的
And I really love this planet.
看看他们有这么多好东西
Look at all the great stuff they've got.
比如这个! 束发带!
Like this! A headband!
如果你要晚礼服的话 你就让它滑下去...
And for evening wear, you slide it down...
成功增肥一圈
you got a beautiful spare tire.
我爱死它了!
I love it!
太棒了!
Very nice!
谁想离开这些东西呢? 我一定要解决这个麻烦
Who would wanna leave this behind? I have got to fix this.
我知道了!
I know!
召集大头波星人
Summon the Big Brain Boovs.
聪明的波星人中的精英
The smarty-pants of all smarty panty Booviness.
先生们...
Gentleboov...
给我出点主意
I want ideas.
我们可以创造一个没有瓜星人的平行宇宙...
We could create an alternate reality with no Gorg in it...
然后搬到那里去
then go live there.
太好了! 我喜欢!
Yes! I love it!
大概需要多久?
How long would that take?
根据我们现有的科技水平...
Based on our current technology...
需要170万年
这时间太长了 托尼 下一个!
That's a lot of years, Toni. Moving on!
- 我们可以躺在地上...  - 然后呢!
- We could lay on the ground...  - Yes!
这样瓜星人就会以为我们都死了
And make the Gorg think we are dead.
下一个!
Next!
我们能不能登陆逃犯波星人的电子邮箱...
What if we logged into the fugitive Boov's email...
然后取消电子邀请函...
and cancelled his e-vite...
嘘! 我们可以登陆逃犯波星人的电子邮箱...
Shush! Or we could log into the fugitive Boov's email...
取消这个邀请函...
and cancel his invitation, and...
然后什么?
What was that?
这样瓜星人就不会收到它了
So the Gorg never receive it.
这样瓜星人就不会收到它了!
So the Gorg never receive it!
现在 把密码输进去 然后取消信息吧
Now, type in the password and cancel that message.
我真聪明 把所有的密码都设成了"mima"
It was a good idea of me to make all passwords "password."
太好记了
It's so easy to remember.
不对! 他的密码是独特的
It did not work! His password is unique.
不!
No!
独特? 波星人从来不是独特的!
Unique? Boov are not unique!
把我的吸入器拿来
Fetch me my inhaler.
天啊 这东西真有用
Boy, that works.
他的错误正在把瓜星人引到我们这里来
His mistaking is leading the Gorg right to us.
让我看看他的邀请函
Show me his invite.
大家来参加我的聚会吧!
You are all invited to a party!
只要到银河系来
Just head to the Milky Way.
到北斗七星右转
Turn right at the Big Dipper.
从太阳开始第三个行星就是
Third planet from the Sun.
来找我的气球吧! 来聚会吧!
Look for my balloons! Party!
如果想玩就来吧!
Come if you like to have fun!
我最好的朋友凯尔也会去哦!
My best friend Kyle will be there!
凯尔 凯尔 凯尔!
Kyle, Kyle, Kyle!
来聚会吧!
Come party!
凯尔!
Kyle!
他不是我的朋友
He is not my friend.
互联网不会说谎!
The internet does not lie!
你认识他 你能找到他的
You know him, you can find him.
我要让你来负责!
I am putting you in charge!
但 长官 这不是我的工作啊 我只是个中级交警
But, Captain, it is not my job. I am only a mid-level traffic Boov.
- 我非常欣赏你这耸样 警官  - 谢谢
- I admire your cowardice, Officer.  - Thank you.
但我要这个星球上所有的波星人警察都来搜这个城市
But I want every Boovcop on Planet Smekland searching this city.
我们需要他的密码...
We need his password...
否则我们就会被瓜星人消灭!
or we will all be destroyed by the Gorg!
找到他!
Find him!
不能让他再出岔子了
That Boov has made his final mistake.
嗒哒!
Fa-da!
你应该把它修好的!
You were supposed to fix it!
这是什么?
What is this?
这叫"雪泥感"
I calls it "Slushious."
"雪泥感"?
"Slushious"?
这当燃料太棒了...
It makes excellent fuel...
而且这口味说上去还很好玩
and comes in fun-to-say flavors.
"逃跑葡萄"
"Grape Escape."
"红橘子旋转"
"Tangerine Twist."
"混蛋柠檬"!
"Busta Lime"!
老妈会杀了我的
Mom's gonna kill me.
现在你可以用人类的传统方式 向我表示感谢了
Now I am prepared to accept one of your traditional gestures of human gratitude.
其实我们的传统是打你的鼻子 别动
Actually, our tradition is to punch you in the nose. Hold still.
不用了! 我已感受到你的谢意
No! Your gratitude is implied.
你可以先开
You can drives first.
然后我再...
Then I can...
你别跟着我
You're not coming.
我要躲避波星人 我才不会让一个波星人在我身边呢
I'm trying to hide from the Boov. I'm not bringing one with me.
你会把我交出去的
You'll just turn me in.
不! 我只是需要你载我一程!
No! I just needs a ride!
我在城的外面有要紧事要办
I haves official Boov business out of in town.
我也是
Me, too.
但我修好了你的车!
But I fixes your car!
那又怎样? 我把你从冰箱里放出来了 我们扯平了
So? I let you out of the freezer. We're even.
- 你对我的车做了什么?  - 什么意思?
- What did you do to my car?  - What doos you mean?
它现在的悬浮性能应该更好了啊
It should to hover much better now.
这是辆车 它以前从来不会悬浮呢
It's a car. It didn't hover at all before.
怎么把这个关掉?
How do you stop this thing?
哦 看来我把前进和后退的指令搞反了
Oops. I have apparently reversing the proceed and anti-proceed controls.
是啊 我发现了 刹车就是油门
Yeah, I noticed. Stop is go.
- 油门就是刹车  - 等等!
- Go is stop.  - Wait!
为什么你这么做? 波星人和人类是朋友!
Whyfor you do this? Boovs and humans are friends!
我们才不是朋友呢 你们绑架了我妈!
We're not friends. You kidnapped my mom!
谁是"我妈"?
Who is Mimom?
不 是"我的"妈妈!
No, "my" mom!
我说什么了?
What did I say?
- 我知道去哪找她  - 怎么找?
- I knows how to find her.  - How?
波星人指挥中心有她在哪儿的信息
That information is at Boov Central Command.
- 在大天线那里  - 啥?
- At the Great Antenna.  - What?
在巴黎! 现在让我进来!
In Paris! Now let me to inside!
巴黎
Paris.
- 那你要保证  - 什么?
- Then promise.  - What?
保证你会帮我找到她 否则我就把你丢下了
Promise you'll help me find her or I'm leaving your Boov butt.
我保证! 但如果你不想被抓住的话 现在就得走!
I promise! But if you do not wish to be capturing, it must be now!
好吧 上车
Fine. Get in.
耶 耶 小猪! 巴黎 我们来咯
Oui, oui, Pig! Paris, here we come.
我们要去看看他们把妈妈抓到哪里去了
We're gonna find out where they put Mom.
好的 我把导航定位到巴黎
Okay. I shall set the GPS to take us straight to the Paris.
目的地: 南极
Destination entered: Antarctica.
嘿 你在干啥?
Hey, what are you doing?
我怎么会输错?
How did that happen?
把你的爪子移开!
Keep your Boov paws off my car!
哦!
Whoa!
你的车子被侵扰了
Your vehicle is infested.
这才不是侵扰呢 他是我的宠物
It's not infested. He's my pet.
他叫小猪 不要碰他
His name is Pig. Don't touch him.
他在震动
Now he is vibrating.
他会爆炸吗?
Is he going to explode?
不会! 他只是在咕噜叫呢
No! He's just purring.
你怎么会有这东西
Why do you haves this thing?
他有用吗? 可以吃他的肉或者喝他的奶吗?
Is it useful? Does it give meat or milk?
什么? 不!
What? No!
你养宠物是为了好玩 而且他能陪着你
You just have pets for fun and companionship.
我也能陪着你啊
You has me for companion on the ship.
是啊 不过 小猪比你好
Yeah, well, Pig is better.
如果猫是"猪" 那你叫什么?
If cat is "Pig," what is your name?
我叫小费·图奇 但我的朋友都叫我小钱
Gratuity Tucci. But my friends call me "Tip."
- 小钱  - 我朋友才能这么叫
- Tip.  - I said "my friends."
但我们是朋友啊 人类和波星人
But we are friends. All humans and Boov.
船长斯麦克说的
Captain Smek has decided.
船长斯麦克是个白痴
Captain Smek is an idiot.
不对!
Untrue!
船长斯麦克太天才了 而且特别会逃跑
Captain Smek is genius and best at running away.
你听过嘘嘘的传说吗?
Have you not heard the legend of the Shusher?
很久以前 我们的敌人 瓜星人...
Long ago, our enemy, the Gorg...
邀请波星人进行和谈
invited the Boov to a peace meeting.
但是斯麦克很聪明地逃跑了
But Smek wisely fled in terror.
而且他还带上了一块战利品: 嘘嘘
And he took a great trophy: the Shusher.
跑啊!
Run away!
为什么要叫"嘘嘘"?
Why is it called the "Shusher"?
嘘!
Shush!
算了
Whatever.
真的假的?
Seriously?
你们把自由女神像毁了?
You guys had to ruin the Statue Of Liberty?
"斯麦克男神像"
"Statue of Smek."
你们会付出代价的
You will not get away with this.
波星人巡警!
Boov Patrol!
他们在找你!
They are looking for you!
哦 不
Oh, no.
哦 不!
Oh, no!
那是什么?
What's that?
嘿!
Hey!
不要让司机分心!
Don't distract the driver!
啊哈 巴塔柠檬味
Aha! Busta Lime.
"巴塔柠檬"
"Busta Lime."
啊哦!
Owpain!
Owpain.
好吧 撒个尿
Okay. Pee break.
我也要去撒个尿
I, too, has to break pee.
你们把它叫做"小号"
Or, as you calls it, the "number one."
- 我们还有"大号"  - 好吧
- We also has the "number two."  - Okay.
- 还有"超大号"  - 好了!
- And the "number three."  - Okay!
幸好我不需要去超大号
It is a good thing I doos not have to go the number three.
否则这对你可不安全
It would not be safe for you.
我们一年只有一次超大号
We only doos it once a year.
我觉得这称不上放假...
I would not call it a holiday...
- 但这一天的确得在家休息  - 够了!
- but you doos need to take the day off.  - That's enough!
你不能进来 这是女卫生间
You can't come in here. This is the girls' room.
不要吃蓝色的薄荷!
Do not eat the blue mints!
谢天谢地 还有一大盆柠檬汁
Thankfully, there is a large bowl of lemonade.
不要喝那个柠檬汁!
Do not drink the lemonade!
马上就出来
Be out in a second.
我们要去巴黎咯!
We're going to Paris!
要见到我妈妈咯!
Going to see my mom!
慢慢来!
Takes your time!
南极洲
Ant-arc-tica.
我来咯!
Here I come!
逃犯波星人
Fugitive Boov.
不要动 你被逮捕了!
Hold still for arresting!
我最好的朋友凯尔!
Best friend Kyle!
我才不是你的朋友呢!
I am not your friend!
不过如果我搞到你的密码我就是英雄波星人了
But I will be a hero Boov for getting your password.
是的! 你来救我了!
Yes! You has in nick-time saved us!
你这表情是什么意思?
What is the purpose of your face?
啊哦
Owpain.
你想抛下我逃跑?
You were gonna ditch me?
- 不!  - 撒谎!
- No!  - Liar!
我从来不撒谎!
I never lie!
你撒谎!
Yes, you do!
你知道我怎么知道的吗?
And you know how I know?
因为每次你撒谎 你都会变绿!
Because every time you lie, you turn green!
才不会呢 我...
I doos not. I...
卧槽
Poomp.
把门打开 你个长得像青蛙的会撒谎的东西!
Open the door, you lying, frog-faced squishy toy!
停! 我需要你的...
Stop! I need your...
你保证要帮我找我妈的!
You promised to help me find my mom!
那我就收回保证!
Then I un-promise!
不能这样的!
That's not how it works!
你必须帮我去巴黎
You have to help me get to Paris.
我不要!
I will not!
停! 我需要你的...
Stop! I need your...
我一定要躲起来!
I must hide!
我在和你说英语 你怎么听不懂呢?
I am speaking the English at you. Whyfor do you not understands me?
我听得懂 但我不关心
I "understands." I just don't care.
- 不要动!  - 小心!
- Freezing!  - Look out!
卧槽!
Come on!
停! 我要你的密码
Stop! I need your password.
不要!
No!
快走!
Go!
我只想要他的密码
All I wanted was his password.
这样的友情可长久不了
This is not a sustainable friendship model.
那么...
So...
我想我们到现在应该已经抓到逃犯了
I assume by now we have apprehended the fugitive.
有人吗?
Anybody?
你 紫色的那个
You. The purple one.
不是这个紫色的 另一个紫色的 那个紫色的
Not that purple. The other purple. The other purple.
就是他
That one.
对了 就是你!
Yes, you!
那他在哪?
So, where is he?
我们不知道 长官
We do not know, sir.
什么? 这是个大灾难!
What? This is number one disaster!
他的信息绝对不能到达瓜星
His message must not reach the Gorg.
我找这个行星可难了 我不要抛弃它!
This planet was hard to find, and I will not abandon it!
谁把我的解压毯子拿来
Someone fetch me my stress blankie.
太棒了
So soothing.
啊哈! 凯尔长官!
Aha! Officer Kyle!
这个波星人最称职了
Now here is a Boov who knows how to do his job.
告诉我 你找到那个通缉犯了?
Tell me, you have found the fugitive?
是的
Yes.
令人惊叹!
Joyful exclamation!
他在哪儿?
And where is he?
出了一点小问题
There is a tiny problem.
"小问题" 小问题而已 管它呢?
"Tiny." As long as it's tiny, who cares?
呃 在我拿到密码之前...
Well, before I got the password...
我把他干掉了
I erased him.
来聚会吧 来聚会吧 来聚会吧
Come party. Come party. Come party.
- 快停下!  - 对不起啊
- Quit it!  - Sorry.
巴黎对我们俩而言都很危险
Look, Paris is danger for both of us.
那里全都是波星人
It crawls with Boov.
我们到那儿以后你有什么计划?
Doos you have a plan for once we are get there?
没有 但是我有希望
Not really. But I have hope.
你数学真差
You are bad at math.
你说什么?
Excuse me?
我可是几何学拿了"A"的人
I got an "A" in geometry.
我只是说...
I am only saying...
波星人更懂计算
Boov are superior in this way.
如果成功的概率低于百分之50...
If probability for success falls below 50%...
波星人就会放弃 但你不会
Boov give up. You do not.
就是这样!
Exactly!
够了 别再撕了!
Enough with the ripping!
好的 好的
Okay, Okay.
告诉你 我们来点音乐吧
Tell you what. Let's have some tuneage.
这是什么?
What is that?
波星人的歌曲
Boov song.
这个叫做 "一动不动要听话"
It is called "Motionless and Obedient."
非常火呢
Very big hit.
不不行! 我车里不行
No, no, no! Not in my car.
司机才有权决定放什么
Driver gets to pick.
这根本不算音乐 不过是噪音
This is not even music. This is just noise.
这是下意识的生理反应
Involuntary physical response.
你骗我听这个有毒的声波武器
You have tricked me into listening to a debilitating sonic weapon.
如果你不想让人类恨你的话...
If you want humans to not hate you...
你可以从喜欢我们的东西开始
you could start by liking some of our stuff.
奇怪 我身体怎么了?
Confusion. What is happening to my body?
这个叫跳舞
It's called dancing!
波星人从来不跳舞
Boov do not dancing!
我看出来了 但你已经跳起来了!
I can tell. But you're getting the hang of it!
这样跳下去多久会死?
How long before this kills me?
我控制不了我的四肢了!
I am not in control of my own extremities!
就是这样 动起来!
That's it. Work it!
我不想这么动!
I do not want it to work!
你知道吗?
You know what?
瞧你多有天份啊
"Boov" rhymes with "groove."
跳起来吧 波星人
Shake your Boov thang.
这么晃好丢人啊!
It is shaking in a most undignified way!
噢 不! 我的手就像不受控制一样挥舞起来了!
Oh, no! My hands are in the air like I just do not care!
这可不是一个波星人应该做的!
This is not how a Boov behaves!
我简直太丢人了!
I am overheated with shame!
- 我必须冷静下来!  - 等等
- I must cool my core!  - Wait!
- 你在干什么?  - 我会回来的!
- What are you doing?  - I will returning!
我们正在玩儿呢!
We were having fun!
噢!
Oh!
哦?
Oh?
够了 妈妈 这不过是雪而已!
Come on, Mom. It's just snow!
我连什么是雪都不知道
I don't know anything about snow.
我们的第一场雪!
Our first snow!
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
我要把这个发给...
I'm sending this to...
我的温度又降回正常了
My temperature is back to happiness.
为了表示我对你没有任何不满...
And to show I do not hold against you any grudge-ment...
我给你带了美味的零食
I have brought you delicious snacking.
伐嗒! 耐嚼的塑料环!
Fa-da! Chewy plastic rings!
我真不喜欢你们人类这种表示感激的方式
I really do not enjoy your human gratitude customs.
你去哪儿了?
Where have you been?
你再也别回来了!
You were gone forever!
这么说不精确 "永远"是指...
That is not accurate. "Forever" is...
我以为你死了! 或者受伤了!
I thought you were dead! Or hurt!
或者... 我也不知道!
Or... I don't know!
但是你不能就这么抛下别人!
But you cannot just leave someone alone like that!
你得穿我的鞋!
Put yourself in my shoes!
我怎么能穿你的鞋?
How could I wears your shoes?
我的脚太小了
My pods are too small.
这是个比喻!
It's an expression!
意思是设身处地为别人考虑
It means try to feel how someone else feels.
我只是个孩子 我不能老是独自一个人呆着
I'm just a kid. I'm not supposed to be by myself all the time.
这是在危害儿童 我告诉你 这是犯罪
This is child endangerment. Which is a crime, by the way.
但是我找到你的时候 你就已经独自一人了...
But when I founded you, you were already alone...
所以我觉得对你而言 这很正常
so I thinks it is normal for you.
我们小的时候 是被养在保温箱里的
When Boov are young, we are kept in the warming oven.
对人类来说这正常吗?
Is this normal for humanspersons?
一般来说 16岁以下我们不独自穿越大西洋
Usually, we don't cross the Atlantic by ourselves until we're 16.
不 这些全都不正常!
No, none of this is normal!
你还不明白吗? 你把一切都毁了!
Don't you get it? You ruined everything!
我好不容易在这儿得到了快乐... 在我生活的地方
I was finally happy here... There, where I lived.
和我妈妈一起
With my mom.
你知道我适应那儿有多不容易吗?
Do you know how hard it was for me to fit in?
花了多长时间?
How long that took?
7年级的女孩都很残忍!
是的 我看到了! 但我不明白!
Yes, I sees that! I did not realize!
我们会继续去找我妈妈
We will resume the finding of Mimom.
别说了!
Stop saying that!
她只是"我"妈妈
She's just "my" mom.
不是你的 我的
Not yours. Mine.
你怎么连这个都不懂?
How do you not understand this?
如果可怕的外星人抓走了你妈妈 你会是什么感觉?
How would you feel if some horrible aliens took your mother from you?
那不可能的
That could not to happen.
波星人没有我妈妈
Boov are not having mimoms.
波星人没有家吗
Boov don't have families.
怪不得你们抢别人的东西 还一点都不放在心上
No wonder you take things and don't care about anybody else.
所以 你的我妈妈...
So, your mimom...
是一个对你很重要的人
is a very important humansperson to you.
比其他人都重要
More important than others.
不在她身边 你会很难过
To not belong with her causes you being sad.
但是刚才 你踢我还对我大吼大叫
But recent moments ago, you are kicking on me and yelling.
这个更像是难过又愤怒
Which is seeming more to be mad than sad.
呃 有时两个都有
Well, sometimes it's both.
所以 你是难过加愤怒
So, you are sad-mad.
人类比手册上写的复杂多了
Humans are more complicated than it said in the pamphlet.
我用最快的速度把这里清空了
I vacuumed here as fast as I could.
你有什么办法能破解那个傻瓜波星人的密码?
Whatfor is your plan for figuring out the dumb Boov's password?
我没办法!
I got nothing!
拜托 快点! 我需要主意!
Please, come on! I need ideas!
你! 那个紫的
You! The purple one.
噢 拜托!
Oh, come on!
所以?
So?
我们可以随便输些数字和字母?
We could type in random numbers and letters?
我喜欢这个主意!
I like it!
给这些大脑充电 开始工作
Get those big brains plugged in and working.
开动!
Away!
你们知道如果瓜星人抓住我们 他们会干什么
You know what the Gorg will do if they find us.
咯 咯 咯(咬牙的声音)
Chomp, chomp, chomp.
这就是为什么我们一直东躲西藏
And that is why we keep running away.
哇喔
Whoa.
为什么瓜星人这么恨你们?
Why do these Gorg hate you so much?
因为他们是瓜星人
Because they are Gorg.
我们把瓜星人称为"掠夺者"...
We calls Gorg the "takers"...
因为如果你有什么东西 他们就会夺走
because if you has something, they takes it.
比如 你有一个三明治
Like, if you has a sandwich.
或者一个星球
Or a planet.
噢 噢 我明白的
No, no. I get it.
不过他们不会到这个星球来的 对吧?
But they're not coming to this planet, right?
噢 不会的 别担心
Oh, no, no. Not to worry.
大头波星人会解决我的错误的
The Big Brain Boov will to fix my mistake.
但是我仍然会被惩罚
But I will still be very punished.
我们有个规矩
We has a rule.
犯九次错 你就出局了
Nine mistakes and you are out.
你犯了多少次错了?
How many mistakes do you have?
62次
当我有压力的时候 我妈妈就会给我讲笑话
When I'm stressed out, my mom tells me jokes.
波星人从来不讲笑话
Boov do not do telling jokes.
这不难 我来教你
It's not that hard. I'll teach you.
咚 咚
Knock, knock.
你要说 "外面是谁?"
You would say, "Who's there?"
你在外面啊
You are there.
不 你就这么问我
No, just ask me.
谁在外面?
Who is there?
然后我说 "插嘴牛"
Now I say, "The interrupting cow."
然后你说 "插嘴牛是谁啊?"
Now you say, "The interrupting cow, who?"
我们开始玩吧
Let's just do it.
- 咚 咚  - 谁在外面?
- Knock, knock.  - Who is there?
插嘴牛
The interrupting cow.
- 插嘴牛...  - 哞!
- The interrupting cow...  - Moo!
我还没有说完呢
You did not let me finish my response.
- 我应该说"插嘴..."  - 哞!
- I was to say, "The interrupting co..."  - Moo!
你又来了一遍
You did it again.
这就是笑话
That is the joke.
那个牛是一个插嘴牛...
The cow is to being an interrupting cow...
所以才打断我说话!
and therefore interrupts me!
- 我知道 所以才好玩  - 哞!
- I know . That's why it's funny.  - Moo!
- 让我说...  - 哞!
- Let me fi...  - Moo!
- 够了  - 我是插嘴牛
- That's enough.  - I'm the interrupting cow.
- 别再说了!  - 哞!
- Knock it off!  - Moo!
- 别逼我再拿胶带!  - 哞!
- Don't make me get out more tape!  - Moo!
这么多波星人!
So many Boovs!
我就说这简直傻透了
I said this was dumbness.
我就说我完蛋了 但是你听了吗? 没有!
I said I am doomed. But doos you listen? No!
噢 够了!
Oh, that's enough!
你快把我逼疯了!
You are driving me to the crazy!
逃跑永远都不嫌晚 这是波星人的名言
It is never too late to run away. That is the Boov motto.
是的 但是我们不逃跑 我有个计划
Yes, but we're not doing that. I have a plan.
你的计划是逃跑吗? 因为除了这个 都傻透了!
Is your plan to run away? Because other-way-wise, it is stupid!
我们只要溜进去...
All we have to do is sneak into the city...
去那个大天线上 用它来找到我妈妈...
get into the Great Antenna, use it to find my mom...
然后再溜出来就行了 看到了吗?
and then sneak out again. See?
这行不通 他们全都认识我
But it still will not work because my face is known.
只要我被任何一个波星人看到 我百分之百会被逮捕的
If I am seen by any Boov, I am 100% popular for being arrested.
要是我能解决这个问题呢?
What if I could fix that?
别动
Hold still.
首先 来一个可爱的小雀斑
First, a little beauty mark.
让我看看
Letting me see.
- 没完呢 把镜子给我  - 给我看 给我看!
- Not yet. Give me that mirror.  - Give to me, give to me!
看上去完全就是一个陌生人!
It is like looking at a completed stranger!
不 还没结束呢 这还没...
No, I'm not done. It's not even...
你简直是个不可思议的化妆师!
You are a worker of miraculous transformation!
这个波星人是谁?
Who is this Boov?
我不知道!
I do not know!
噢 好吧
All right, Oh.
哎呦
Owpain.
高速电梯启动中
Express elevator departing.
哇喔!
Whoa!
简直令人大开眼界
This is uber freaky.
这些都是你们最聪明的波星人吗?
These are the smartest Boov you have?
你必须非常安静
You must be very quiet.
你不能分散他们的注意力...
You do not want to break their concentra...
来聚会吧 来聚会吧
Come party. Come party.
噢! 那是什么?
Oh! What is it?
我以为大头波星人已经终止了发送邀请信息
I thought the Big Brain Boovs would have stopped my invitation by now.
可是他们竟然还没有找到我的密码
But they have still not figured out my password.
- 这怎么可能呢?  - 等一下
- How is this possible?  - Wait a minute.
这东西意思是说 那些叫瓜星人的怪物会到地球来?
Does this mean those horrible monster Gorg thingies will come to Earth'?
对的 来斯麦克星!
To Smekland, yes!
然后会怎么样呢?
And what happens then?
我们就再也找不到我妈妈了!
There will be no finding of Mimom!
那你必须解决这个问题!
Then you've gotta fix this!
对
Yes.
快点!
Hurry!
顺便问一下 你的头骨有弹性吗?
By to the way, is your skull flexible?
- 什么?  - 别管了
- What?  - Never mind.
应该没问题的 别动
It will be probably okay. Hold still.
哇喔!
Wow!
还有30秒就完蛋了
我得输入我的密码 是...
I shall input my password. It is...
"我的名字叫小欧 斯麦克船长非常伟大 谁不这么想谁就是傻子 1"
"My name is Oh and Captain Smek is great and anyone who does not think that is a poomp 1."
我很奇怪怎么会没人想的出来
I wonder why no one guessed that.
我不知道
I do not know.
- 不起作用?  - 不可能!
- It didn't work?  - Impossible!
密码就是这个!
That is password!
这个就是... 噢 不! 大写锁定
That is... Oh, no! Caps Lock.
快点 快点 快点!
Come on, come on, come on!
来聚会吧 来聚会吧 来聚会吧
Come party. Come party. Come party. Come party.
来聚会吧 来聚会吧
Come party. Come party.
太好了!
Yes!
伐嗒! 成功了
Fa-da! It has worked.
成功了!
It worked!
你成功了!
You did it, Oh!
好悬呐
That was closeness.
站起来
On your feet.
你还是得找到我妈妈
You still have to find my mom.
这太简单了 我们现在就搜索...
That is simplicity. We shall now searching on...
露西·图奇
Lucy Tucci.
"露西·图奇"
"Lucy Tucci."
澳大利亚?
Australia?
寻找我妈妈
Observe Mimom.
这可不好笑
That's not funny.
这不是你的我妈妈?
This is not your mimom?
你逗我呢?
Are you kidding?
不是她!
That's not her!
你确定?
Sure?
我知道 好吗?
I know, I know. Okay?
你已经说了两个星期了
You've been saying that for two weeks.
求你了!
Please!
她有一双大的绿色的眼睛还有美丽的棕色皮肤
She has big green eyes and beautiful brown skin.
妈妈
Mom.
告诉我她在哪
So tell me where she is.
或者找个知道她在哪的波星人
Or find me a Boov who can.
求你了
Please.
小费·图奇 你看起来简直就是小号的我妈妈
Gratuity Tucci looks just like tiny Mimom.
小费·图奇? 你...
Gratuity Tucci? Whyfor...
谢谢! 谢谢 谢谢 谢谢 谢谢!
Thank you! Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you!
真不敢相信! 我妈妈居然在澳大利亚!
I can't believe it! My mom's in Australia!
而且我取消掉了我的邀请!
And I has cancelled my e-vite!
我终于不用到处躲了
I can finally come out of the hiding.
对!
Yes!
瞧瞧你
Well, well, well.
人呢?
Hello?
拿着我的皇冠
Hold my crown.
小心点 这可是唯一一个
And be very careful. It's the only one.
瞧瞧你
Well, well, well.
你真的以为你能逃出去?
Did you really think you could escape?
逃? 没 没 没
Escape? No, no, no.
你看 我才准备过来告诉你...
You see, I was just coming to tell you...
尽管你使用了复杂的伪装...
Despite your elaborate disguise...
电脑依旧可以把你识别为
the computer recognized you as...
逃亡的波星人
the fugitive Boov!
但是他现在是英雄波星人了!
But he's a hero Boov now!
是啊! 我改正了我的错误!
Yes! I has fixed my mistake!
是 但是在这之前你犯了错
Yes, but before that, you has made your mistake.
并且以前还犯过很多错误
And many mistakes before that.
- 等等 我没有...  - 好多好多好多
- Wait, I have not...  - Many, many, many, many...
其实...
Actually...
好多错误
Many mistakes before that.
- 所以我还是要消灭你  - 为什么?
- So, I still has to erase you.  - Why?
你不能保证你以后不会再犯错误了
You cannot guarantee you would not make a mistake again.
- 但是我不会了  - 但你可能
- But I would not.  - But you might.
但是我不会了
But I would not.
我们可以来回说 再来一次!
We could go round and round. Let's do it again!
- 但是我不会了  - 但你可能
- But I would not.  - But you might.
- 但是我不会了  - 我喜欢这个!
- But I would not.  - I love this!
- 但是我不会了!  - 好无聊
- But I would not!  - Bored now.
- 但是我不...  - 闭嘴!
- But I would...  - Shush!
消灭他!
Erase him!
放下你们的气泡枪!
Drop the bubble guns!
不然我就弄坏这个...
Or I will mess with this...
重力仪
gravity thingy.
她吹牛
She is bluffing.
她根本碰不到重力仪
She could not possibly reach the gravity thingy.
我诅咒你这该死的身高!
Curse you and your tippy-toe tallness!
但是没问题
But no problem.
波星人的技术对于你这种思想简单的人类女孩来说太复杂了
Boov technology is far too complicated for simple humansgirl to figure out.
你说什么?
Excuse me?
这个人类女孩的几何是 "A"
This humansgirl got an "A" in geometry.
她弄明白了! 快跑啊!
She figured it out! Run for my life!
都闪开! 我是船长!
Out of my way! I am captain!
抓住!
Grab on!
不行! 我抓不住你!
Oh, no! I can't hold you!
你太沉了!
You weigh, like, a thousand pounds!
松手
Let go.
- 什么?  - 相信我
- What?  - Trust me.
不好意思 我有权利先逃跑
Sorry. It is my duty to run away first.
嘭
Poomp.
- 你等什么呢?  - 我不能碰它
- What are you waiting for?  - I cannot touch.
如果我开的话它是不会飞的
It will not work if I drive it.
好吧 我来开
Fine. I'll drive.
好疼
Owpain.
你驾驶技术太差了
You are terrible driver.
加油啊
Come on.
加油 加油
Come on. Come on.
用餐愉快
Bon appétit.
不 你才不会呢
Oh, no, you don't!
我是不会付钱的
I am not paying for that.
别这样啊 你这蠢马
Come on, you stupid horse!
呼 好险...
Whoo, that was cl...
这次我抓到你了...
This time I got you...
你跑不了了
and you cannot escape.
检测到在逃波星人
Fugitive Boov detected.
我错了
I was wrong.
跳啊!
Jump!
哦 不!
Oh, no!
看! 我找到我们的车了
Look! I has found our car.
小猪!
Pig!
我不知道你为什么要拿那个
I do not know whyfor you brought that.
我们车里已经有食物了
We already hads food in the car.
这不是食物 这是艺术
It's not food, it's art.
那它一定不好
Then it is bad.
行星才不是那样的呢
Stars do not look like that.
这和它们的长相没关系
It's not about how they look.
这和他们给你的感觉有关
It's about how they feel.
他们很热
They feel hot.
好吧 数学能手 我们多长时间可以到澳大利亚?
Okay, math whiz, how long till we get to Australia?
17.9348个小时
然后 小费·图奇...
And then, Gratuity Tucci...
就会见到我妈妈
will see Mimom.
听到了吗 小猪?
You hear that, Pig?
我都等不及告诉妈妈我来过巴黎了...
I can't wait to tell Mom I actually went to Paris...
她一直都想来这里
which you know she always wanted to do.
我们可以一起回来这里
Maybe we could both come back here.
我们现在有会飞的车了
We do have a flying car now.
法语的猫怎么说?
How do you say "cat" in French?
我觉得应该是 "聊"
I think it's "chat."
你这是什么表情?
What is the purpose of your face?
我很困惑
I has confusion.
我不想被消灭
I do not wish to be erased.
但船长斯麦克可能是对的
But maybe Captain Smek is right.
我很可能再犯低级错误
It is possible I will continue making hilarious mistakes.
可能吧
Probably.
这可不会让我开心
That is not making me feel better.
人无完人
Nobody's perfect.
我妈妈说犯错是人的本性
My mom says your mistakes are what make you human.
可不是波星人的本性
That is not what makes you Boov.
小费·图奇...
Gratuity Tucci...
在我们来之前...
before we came...
船长斯麦克告诉我们 人类需要我们的帮助
Captain Smek telled us that the humans needed us.
人类就像是动物一样...
That the humans were just like the animals...
我们可以让他们变得更好...
and that we could to make them better...
教化他们
teach to them.
我们被告知人类是简单落后的种族
We were told the humans were simple and backwards.
这就是我们的看法
It is what we thought.
但是 我现在觉得
But I am thinking now...
我们的看法错了
that we were thinking wrong.
船长斯麦克是最错的那个
And that Captain Smek is the wrongest.
我认为波星人就不应该来斯麦克星
I am thinking the Boov should never have come to Smekland.
来地球
To Earthland.
我想说 很抱歉
So I am saying the sorry to you...
小费·图奇
Gratuity Tucci.
叫我小钱就好
Call me Tip.
那是一个新家 新国度
It was a new home, a new country.
我试图在学校里交朋友...
I tried to make friends at school...
但我却是个来自巴巴多斯的书呆子
but I was this nerd from Barbados.
但是你的几何是A啊
But you dids to get an "A" in geometry.
是啊
Yeah, I did.
我知道当别的波星人说 "欧" 的时候...
I know when the other Boovs said "Oh"...
他们是不想看到我
they were not happy to see me.
事实是 在波星人里 我和他们不合群
The true is, among Boov, I do not fit in.
他们排斥我
I fit out.
她特别棒
She is so amazing.
她会留下所有的东西...
She saved up everything she had...
这样我们就能搬家并且可以生活得好一点
so we could move and things would be better for us.
我等不及去见我妈妈了
I cannot wait to meet Mimom.
"我是船长斯麦克 嘘 嘘 嘘"
"My name is Captain Smek. Shush, shush, shush."
"波星人的技术对于你这种思想简单的人类女孩来说太复杂了"
"Boov technology is far too complicated for simple humansgirl to figure out."
他们是怎么发现我们的?
How did they find us?
我不知道啊!
I do not know!
等等 他们没有攻击
Wait. They're not attacking.
因为他们在逃跑
Because they are running away.
他们为什么逃跑?
Why are they running away?
原因只有一个
There can only be one reason.
瓜星人来了
Gorg.
这怎么可能 我把信号断掉了啊
This makes no sense. I stopped the message.
瓜星人找不到我们
Gorg cannot to finding us.
那他们怎么来的?
Then how did they?
一定还有别的原因!
There must be some other reason!
哦 在我们身后
Oh, behind us!
启动武器系统
Engage weapons system.
我们还有武器系统?
We have a weapons system?
发射卷饼鱼雷!
Go, Burrito Torpedo!
真棒!
Yes!
我们中弹了! 我们失去"逃跑的葡萄"了!
We've been hit! We're losing Grape Escape!
我们失去"扭曲橘子"了!
We lost Tangerine Twist!
如果我们再失去布斯塔莱姆 我就没法控制了!
If we lose Busta Lime, I cannot control!
系好安全带! 我们要坠毁了!
Click and ticket. We are to crash!
天哪!
Oh!
不要啊
No, no, no.
雪泥感! 不要啊!
Slushious! No!
别光站着啊! 帮忙来!
Don't just stand there! Help!
不要啊!
Come on, come on, come on!
雪泥感! 不要啊!
Slushious! No!
她坏了
She's gone.
我们完蛋了
We are doomed.
我们永远都去不了澳大利亚了
Now I'll never make it to Australia.
我来唱波星人死亡之歌
I will now sing the Boov Death Song.
有一艘瓜星人飞船!
A Gorg ship!
打断死亡之歌是很不礼貌的
It is rude to interrupt the Death Song.
你可以拆掉它的零件来修我们的车
Maybe you could take the parts from it to fix our car.
我不行 那是瓜星人的零件 它们用的是公制单位
I cannot. Those are Gorg parts. They are metric.
我们马上就要到了 不能放弃
We're not getting this close and giving up.
- 来吧  - 不!
- Come on.  - No!
到处乱跑总是会有危险的
Always with the running towards danger.
别这么胆小了 这是我们唯一的机会了 来吧
Stop being such a Boov. It's our only chance. Come on.
这成功率很低!
This has low probability of success!
- 走吧  - 等等!
- Let's go.  - Wait!
等什么?
For what?
等你反悔
For you to change your mind.
走吧
Come on.
里面没有飞行员
There's no pilot.
这是个无人机
It is just a drone.
被严重损坏
That could have been badness.
但我们还是不安全
But we are not safety.
瓜星人的母舰很快就会到这里了
Gorg mothership will be here soon enough.
你能找到有用的东西吗?
Can you use any of this?
坏的
Broken.
没用
Useless.
很可能导致核裂变
Likely to cause thermonuclear fission.
那是什么?
What is it?
瓜星人的超级芯片!
It is Gorg super-chip!
为什么叫超级芯片?
Why is it called a super-chip?
叫这名字好卖
It is mostly marketing.
但它是
But it is key...
让瓜星人的机器强于所有机器的关键
for the Gorg are having machines that are stronger and better at everything.
所以我们和他们永远不可能有公平的战斗
So we can never fight them with equaltude.
我们能用它来修雪泥感吗?
Can we use it to fix Slushious?
能 能! 雪泥感会再次起飞的
Yes, yes! The Slushious will fly again.
太棒了!
Yes!
成功率很低
It was low probability of success.
你能行
Some Boov you are.
快点
Quickly.
我们必须修好雪泥感 然后找到我妈妈
We must fix the Slushious and find Mimom.
是 "我" 妈妈
"My" mom.
我就是这么说的啊
That is the thing I said.
我就知道会成功的!
I knew this would all work out!
你太棒了!
You were awesome!
我们会找到我妈妈...
We're gonna find my mom...
你要给大家展示你的超级芯片并成为一个大英雄...
you're gonna show everybody the super-chip and be a big hero...
甚至是船长斯麦克都要...
and even Captain Smek will have to...
好多人啊
That's a lot of people.
- 再见 波星人!  - 快点走吧!
- Bye, Boov!  - Get lost!
哇 你们还真是挺会跑路的啊
Wow. You guys really are good at running away.
是啊
Yes.
我们确实挺会的
Yes, we are.
快看 在那!
Look, over there!
我看到妈妈曾在那个地方!
That's where we saw my mom!
快点 这是最后一艘船了!
Hurry up, it is the last ship!
没事的 小猪 我会带妈妈一起回来的
It's okay, Pig. I'll be back with Mom.
我们快到啦!
We're almost there!
这边
Over here.
- 什么啊?  - 快点!
- What?  - Hurry!
我不明白 她在那里吗?
I don't understand. She's in there?
是的
Yes.
说实话
Tell me the truth.
没时间了
There is no time.
你可以和我一起走
You can come with me.
你会很安全的
You will be safety.
我妈根本没在那艘船上 是不是?
My mom's not on that ship, is she?
你答应过我要帮我找到她 可你现在却要走了?
You promised to help me find her, and you're leaving?
- 你个大骗子  - 不是这样的!
- You lied to me. - No!
骗人不是件好事
A lie is a bad thing.
可我却因此救了你啊
I did a thing so you can live.
我妈在这里 我才不走
I'm not going. My mom is here.
你绝对找不到她的
You will never find her.
百分之百找不到
It is 100%.
待在这里没有任何希望
Staying now does not make hope.
瓜星人的母舰很快就要来了
Gorg mothership will be here soon.
它会摧毁这个星球的
It destroys planets.
- 我们必须现在就走!  - 我不要!
- We must run away now!  - No!
原来是真的
It is true.
人类竟然连这么简单明了的事情都想不明白
Humanspersons cannot even understand simple, simple things.
我是在救你! 我是你的朋友
I am saving you! I am being your friend.
没有 你只是在逃命
No, you're just running away.
我们不能抛弃自己的家人
You don't leave your family.
但你无法理解这个道理
But you can't understand that...
因为你只是个波星人!
because you're just a Boov!
你我从来就不是一类的
You've never been my friend.
等等!
Wait!
最后逃离飞船马上就要起飞
Final escape pod departing.
我讨厌瓜星人! 他们总能找到我们
I hate upon the Gorg! They are always finding us!
瓜星人的母舰!
The Gorg mothership!
我们死定了!
We are doomed!
快逃啊!
Run away!
快让开 我抱着孩子呢
Make a path, I'm holding a baby.
是那个逃犯!
It is the fugitive Boov!
他怎么往母舰那边跑!
He is running towards the danger!
快拦住他!
Stop him!
不要啊!
Undo!
船长 我们的飞船达到了史上最高速
Captain, we are achieving new highest speeds!
你做了什么啊? 那是个什么东西?
What has you done? What is that thing?
瓜星人的超级芯片
It is Gorg super-chip.
啥?
What?
瓜星人的无人机坠毁...
Gorg drone crashed...
被我碰巧撞上 然后我就发现了这个芯片
and I ran to it and I found the chip.
够了
Enough.
你碰上了瓜星人?
You ran to a Gorg?
他居然直面危机?
He runs towards the danger?
他是个怎样的波星人啊?
What kind of Boov is he?
他简直是超级波星人
He is like a Super Boov.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
他才不是什么超级波星人
He is not a Super Boov.
在这艘船上只有一个超级波星人 并且你们知道我说的是谁
There is only one Super Boov on this ship, and you know who it is.
近在眼前哦
You're looking at him.
是我组织的大逃亡
I invented running away.
还有看这里 我有嘘嘘棒
And look at this. I have the Shusher.
我才是你们的船长
I am your captain.
但你不是个合格的船长
But you are not good captain.
什么?
What?
你告诉了我们很多事 我们都信了
You telled us these things, and we all believed them.
起码我相信了
I believed them.
直到我遇见一个人类
But then I met a humansperson.
她却并不像你所说的那样
And she is not like you said.
她勇敢 聪明
She is brave and smart...
关心其他的人类
and cares about other humanspersons.
可我们波星人却从来都不会关心彼此
In a way that we Boov do not even care about each other.
她甚至还很关心我
She even cares about me.
虽然我并不值得她这么做
And I've done very little to earn that.
或许波星人在许多方面都很优秀
The Boov may be superior in many ways...
那是自然
Yeah.
但却疏忽了最重要的东西
but not in the ways that I now thinks are most important.
得了吧
Big deal!
我听够了 给我闭嘴!
I have had enough. Shush!
你才给我闭嘴
That is enough shushing.
你居然敢叫我闭嘴!
How dare you shush a shushing!
小欧说得对 我们需要一个新的船长
Oh is right. We need a new captain.
我认为小欧是不二人选
I thinks it should be Oh!
我? 不行的
Me? No.
不行! 他才不配当船长
No! He cannot be captain.
我有嘘嘘棒 我才是船长!
I have the Shusher. I am captain!
再也不是了!
Not anymore!
他不知道怎么控制这个的
He will not know how to operate it!
这个非常复杂的
It is very complicated.
一头重 一头轻
Heavy on one end, light on the other.
闭嘴!
Shush!
棒!
Booyah!
不 我真的不配领导波星人
No, I am not a Leader Boov.
我犯了太多太多错误
I makes far too many mistakes.
你又不是唯一一个犯错误的波星人
You are not the only Boov who makes mistakes.
比如说...
For examples...
我最大的错误就是没做你的朋友
My mistake is not being your friend.
大家为小欧船长欢呼吧!
All hail Captain Oh!
我看到是谁干的了!
I saw who did that!
你给我等着瞧!
I hold grudges, you know!
小欧 你是最棒的!
Oh, you're the best!
想不想办个派对 小欧?
Want me to host party, Oh?
走开啦
Go away.
不对 你应该说 "是谁?"
No, you are supposed to be saying "Who is there?"
然后我就会说
Then I am to be saying...
"哞!"
"Moo!"
小欧!
Oh!
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe it!
可是我看到你们的飞船飞走了啊!
But I saw your ship leave!
但你却回来了 你还来这干什么?
But you came back! What are you doing here?
这里才是我心之所在
It is where I belongs.
你和小猪是我的朋友
You and Pigcat are my friends.
还有...
And alsos, too...
我答应过你的
I gave you a promise.
他是我的朋友
He's my friend.
谢谢你
Thank you.
妈妈
Mom.
小钱 我的乖女儿
Tippy. My beautiful girl.
妈妈 我到处找你
I've been looking everywhere, Mom.
我好害怕我们再也见不到了
I was so scared we'd never see each other again.
妈妈 我永远都不会放弃找你的
Mom, I never would have stopped looking until I found you.
他们还在找我们
They are still looking.
瓜星人不是掠夺者
Gorg are not the takers.
波星人才是
Boov are.
我们必须得等会再互诉衷肠了
We must demonstrate our affections later.
还有一个问题没解决
There is still one problem.
请问那是什么?
Excuse me, what is that?
那是瓜星人的母舰 它来摧毁这个星球了
That is Gorg mothership. It is here to destroy the planet.
它会毁了这个星球?
It's going to destroy the planet?
是的 但我有个主意
Yes. But I haves a plan.
小欧?
Oh?
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
对不起
I am sorry.
小钱现在不能出来
Tip cannot come into the out now.
我要弥补我的过错
I am fixing my mistake.
小欧 你不能一个人做这件事!
Oh! You can't do this on your own!
也许是不能
Maybe not.
但我还是心存希望
But I haves hope.
不!
No!
停下 别!
Stop, no!
不要自己一个人去啊!
Please don't do this by yourself!
不! 不要!
No! Don't!
小欧!
Oh!
快停下!
Stop!
快看呐!
Look!
嘿!
Hey!
瓜星人!
Gorg!
光喊没什么用
It is useless to yell.
瓜星人!
Gorg!
他们看不见他
They're not gonna see him.
根本不行啊!
It's not gonna work!
圣诞节快乐
Merry Christmas.
- 现在?  - 快打开
- Now?  - Just open it.
亲爱的 谢谢 但...
Thank you, sweetheart, but what...
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
让驾驶员分心
Distracting the driver.
起作用了! 母舰停下来了！
It worked! The ship's stopping!
但却不能及时停下来！
It's not gonna stop in time!
快停下来!
Stop faster!
他要赶紧离开那儿！
He's gotta get out of there!
妈妈 快帮我搞定这东西
Mom, help me with this thing!
小欧!
Oh!
快跑!
Run!
小钱!
Tip!
快停下来!
Stop!
小钱!
Tip!
妈!
Mom!
小欧!
Oh!
你还活着
You're alive.
但是你吓死我了!
But you scared me so bad!
你吓坏啦?
You were scared?
我也差点吓"屎"了
I almost made a number three.
也不是很难
Not too hard!
还是存在可能性的
It is still a possibility.
你们说了什么啊?
What was all that?
不是所有的瓜星人语言都能对应成人类的语言
Not all Gorg-speak has humans words.
但显然 瓜星人不是因为我的邀请来这里的
But, it turns out, Gorg was not here because of my invitation...
虽然瓜星人还蛮乐意参加的
though Gorg would have been happy to attend.
瓜星人来这是因为追踪到这块石头
Gorg was here because Gorg was tracking the rock.
里面装的是什么?
What was in that thing?
瓜星人的族系
Gorg family.
他们的整个后代族系
It is entire next generation.
整个?
All of them?
整个
All of them.
难怪他们要一直追着你了
No wonder they've been chasing you.
不是 "他们" 是 "他"
Not "they," "he."
显然 那个瓜星人是他们星球最后一个了
Apparently, that Gorg is last Gorg.
所以这块石头才会如此重要
That is why rock was so important.
没有这块石头 他就会非常寂寞...
Without it, he was alonely...
接着在某一天就灭绝了...
and would someday be extinctly...
这才让瓜星人变得古怪 不通情理...
which made Gorg cranky and irrational...
并且还有暴力倾向
and physically violent.
他其实就像人类女孩一样
He was just like humansgirl.
只是伤心得发疯了
He was sad-mad.
谢谢你
Thanking you.
谢谢你! 漂亮的击掌
Thanking you! High hand touching.
对 这里 再来个
Yeah, give it here. High hand touching.
再高点! 你太慢啦
Up high! You are too slow.
击掌! 这下好痛
High hand touching! That hurt.
两周后
小猪猫咪!
Pigcat!
嘿 小欧!
Hey, Oh!
你好啊 我的朋友凯尔
Hello, friend Kyle.
我也有一样的颜色
I have that same color.
- 嗨 我妈妈  - 嗨 小欧
- Hi, Mimom.  - Hi, Oh.
小欧! 这个派对太棒啦!
Awesome party, Oh!
有人参加的派对才更加有趣嘛!
Parties are so much more fun when other people show up.
是时候该把场子再弄热一些了吧?
Is it time to pick it up a level?
当然!
Yes!
那会更加热闹的!
This is gonna be sweet!
让我们一起发烧起来吧
Drop it like it has a high temperature!
哎呀 不是吧!
Oh, no!
我的身体怎么回事?
What is happening to my body?
一起摇摆起来吧!
Shake your Boov thang!
我的手好像不自觉得就举起来了!
My hands are in the air like I just do not care!
我有了新的开始 新的家 还有新的朋友
I has a new start in a new home with new friends.
现在 每天都是最棒的一天!
And now, every day is best day ever!
你们都受邀参加我的派对 派对 派对
You are all invited to a party, party, party.
银河系直走 然后在北斗星右拐
Just head to the Milky Way, turn right at the Big Dipper.
太阳系第三颗行星
Third planet from the Sun.
看看我的气球!
Look for my balloons!
来我的派对吧!
Come party!
大家 茄子!
Everybody, smile!
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: 千欲 小黄不小黄 夏至未寒 肉肉君 喵喵
校对: 你们茶前辈